Differences between a DFSS and PFSS Project
Welcome to this session on Design for Six Sigma.
Or what we call DFSS Design for Six Sigma.
This is a very, very powerful concept, and normally follows Processing for Six Sigma.
Remember the aim of Processing for Six Sigma, PFSS.
Here's a scale of measure.
Here is a performance distribution, say of some CTQ.
And, let's suppose that, here's the target.
Thus, the average of this distribution,
is right there. That's the center of the capability that you have.
Notice it’s separated from the target.
There's the target. And it's off location.
Well, what's our goal of PFSS? Our goal is to take that distribution and put it on center.
And narrow the variation.
See, that's our goal. We’re going to zoom in there and really start to focus on that.
Processing for Six Sigma is about
putting the center of that distribution on the target
and concurrently narrowing the spread. The variation.
Cause remember, that variation is the enemy. It constitutes uncertainty.
And we want to remove uncertainty.
We want to make our processes operate as certain as possible.
Now this is all fine and well but it's relative to something.
What is that goal relative to? It’s relative to this target.
Who sets that target? Recall here, if I look at this,
I can view this as an is condition.
Is. See, there's the average. That's the is.
And the target here is the ought. And the difference is a delta.
Or gap, as we call it.
Now who sets this?
Who is responsible out there, to determine what ought to be?
Obviously, we know how to determine is, we do that through PFSS.
The ought is done through DFSS.
And that's what we’re going to explore as we talk about Design for Six Sigma.
How to set the expectations, such as the upper spec limit, the target,
and the lower specification limits?
How do we set the standards? The performance expectation?
How do we establish the window of operation for our CTQ’s?
That's what Design for Six Sigma is about. Setting those standards and expectations.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.